Speaker 1: So we played a game that I don't know if Scott's going to play because, you know, Scott of Geek Night's Fame doesn't necessarily.
Speaker 1: he likes to give recommendations of games to play, to give recommendation to watch.
Speaker 1: But what he doesn't ever like to do is receive recommendations.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the more you recommend something, the more resistant he will be to actually consuming said media.
Speaker 0: It will always be like it's going in the queue and then following that will be like, stop bugging me to play X game and watch X movie.
Speaker 0: And I hate television.
Speaker 0: And so I think rather than just, you know, harping on him to try to get him to play this game, we figured we'd we'd just jump ahead.
Speaker 1: And because we already played it and it was fantastic.
Speaker 1: And it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a game that I highly recommend that geek nights listeners play.
Speaker 0: It was it was funny because you basically did the thing that I just described where you played it and then you were on my case for like a couple of weeks.
Speaker 0: Be like, oh, my gosh, you have to play this game.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about this game with somebody.
Speaker 0: I have to, you know, see your thoughts on it and see what decisions you make.
Speaker 0: And the only other game I can remember you doing that with was Disco Elysium.
Speaker 0: And I one thing that I really have been liking is there is a. it's not really a genre of game, but there's a certain type of game that I call couch games because they're not real time.
Speaker 0: They're not like super competitive.
Speaker 0: They're more narrative based.
Speaker 0: And so we both play them kind of together.
Speaker 0: Usually one person's kind of driving it and the other one is either spectating or, you know, contributing like we played Night in the Woods, basically where we both decide what to do together.
Speaker 0: And so that was how I played half of Disco Elysium, which you had already played.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that was how we played Night in the Woods.
Speaker 0: And this is like the third game we've really done the couch gaming with.
Speaker 1: So it's it's Slay the Princess, which I think I mentioned a few times on Geek Night.
Speaker 1: So I think it's very good.
Speaker 1: For those of you who are unaware, it's a recent game and it was put out by Black Tabby Games, which was co-founded by Abby Howard.
Speaker 1: Now, you may remember Abby Howard as the famous strip search contestant who she's gone on to make games.
Speaker 1: And this is one of her games.
Speaker 1: It is like 17 bucks on Steam.
Speaker 1: Full disclosure.
Speaker 1: It's not the sort of cheapo indie game that we often talk about.
Speaker 1: I think that's part of why Scott won't play it.
Speaker 1: But honestly, 20 bucks, 17 bucks for a game like this is a reasonable price.
Speaker 1: I got that much entertainment out of it.
Speaker 1: And if you want to support indie games that are charging what it costs to make them, this is a better way to go.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess what I thought about it like is it costs at least 20 dollars to get an indie published graphic novel.
Speaker 1: You know, even even we paid 20 bucks each just to see Deadpool.
Speaker 1: And that was far less entertainment per minute total than this game was.
Speaker 0: And and think about like, you know, you will pay five bucks for a black and white zine that has interesting story.
Speaker 0: But this has like since it's so branching, it's like a zine, but also a tree of zines.
Speaker 0: And so you're paying paying like 20 bucks for a tree of of indie comic zines.
Speaker 1: So the game will review it first pretty briefly, because the game is very straightforward.
Speaker 1: It's a very simple game.
Speaker 1: And then we're going to worry about spoilers.
Speaker 1: Then we're going to talk about the game as we've played it.
Speaker 0: Just straight up.
Speaker 0: The title really gives away what the game is about on its surface.
Speaker 0: It's like the cliche of saving the princess is basically turned on its head.
Speaker 0: And you are asked from the first moments of the game to slay the princess.
Speaker 1: It's it's framed like an adventure game visual novel.
Speaker 1: You literally like you're on a road leading to a cabin.
Speaker 1: There is a princess in the cabin.
Speaker 1: There's a knife in the cabin.
Speaker 1: You've got to go kill that princess.
Speaker 1: Don't ask questions.
Speaker 1: And the entire game is just reacting to that prompt.
Speaker 0: The narrator, because you start in a forest and the narrator, it's very similar to, you know, I worked on Colossal Cave remake with the Williamses and the type of narration is very similar to how it it plays in those old you know, technically it was originally text based.
Speaker 0: But then when they they do it with voiceover, it's often like a voice is telling you things and you're supposed to take in information from the voice.
Speaker 1: But it's also very evocative of the Stanley parable in that the narrator is also narrating what you're doing and reacting to you.
Speaker 1: And the narrator, much like the Stanley parable, is a character with its own motivations and unreliability is.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, maybe maybe you believe the narrator or not.
Speaker 1: Maybe you trust what that character says or not.
Speaker 1: But the narrator is motivated and a part of the story.
Speaker 1: And the whole game is just very simple, sketchy, semi animated drawings.
Speaker 1: You know, Abby Howard did all the art, from what I can tell.
Speaker 1: It's got some pretty good music in the background.
Speaker 1: It's got two voice actors and it won't take you that long to be.
Speaker 1: This is like an afternoon's worth of play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think one thing that I was kind of struck about was the fact that it has a kind of, you know, it's got this very like I made the comparison to indie comics.
Speaker 0: It's all black and white.
Speaker 0: And, you know, it does feel like a web comic or something like that.
Speaker 0: But it's got this very fascinating effect that they even warn you about it.
Speaker 1: Well, the game's booting up a good amount of accessibility features for a visual novel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like some people get dizzy from the parallax effect.
Speaker 0: So, you know, keep that in mind.
Speaker 0: You know, we don't want you to get motion sick.
Speaker 0: But I found it to be really, really an interesting.
Speaker 0: It just added that little bit of visual polish to the game where there's like a certain amount of parallax between the foreground elements and the background elements and the world kind of shifts.
Speaker 0: And, you know, there's.
Speaker 0: there are some other artistic effects they add later in the game that I think they're very simple, but they add not just to the visuals, but also kind of set a tone or mood to certain scenes.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I mean, it's categorized like in genre wise, like on Steam.
Speaker 1: It's called a dating sim, which I can see.
Speaker 1: I can see why.
Speaker 1: Partly there are some endings that are possible that we didn't explore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, new psychological horror with the specific subnote of body horror.
Speaker 0: Yes, there's definitely body horror.
Speaker 0: And one thing that I think, you know, this game, it should.
Speaker 0: it's not super gruesome, but it definitely should.
Speaker 0: If you have a lot of, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Kind of reaction to gore, like you need a trigger warning for something like, you know, seeing a bone, you know, maybe.
Speaker 1: It's a sketchy smile, but there is a there can potentially be a lot of gore and death for what is a visual novel of someone sent to slay a princess in the cabin in the woods.
Speaker 1: Gore and vore in this game.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, definitely don't necessarily take your first few minutes or the introductory title screen or anything like that as, oh, the game is just going to look like this and it has a humanoid princess and she's going to be like such and such.
Speaker 0: There's there's a lot of kind of spooky stuff, shall we say, in this game?
Speaker 0: And horror is definitely.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say that horror is its primary thing.
Speaker 1: Well, it can.
Speaker 1: that can be its primary thing.
Speaker 1: This game reacts to you as a player.
Speaker 1: And I guess where this succeeds, where a lot of visual novels and a lot of branching narrative games really fail for me is that it is meticulously designed so that every possible path is, I would say, equally satisfying, but more importantly, equally valid.
Speaker 1: Like there's no correct path through this game.
Speaker 1: A lot of visual novels will have the good path, the true path, the path you're expected to take.
Speaker 1: And the game even tells you in the very beginning, the game explicitly says there are no premature endings, meaning you can just play it through and you'll always get a full game no matter what decisions you make.
Speaker 1: You can't die in a way that prevents you from fully experiencing the game.
Speaker 0: I also think it's very interesting that it feels like it ends really soon.
Speaker 0: And then upside down, something happens again.
Speaker 0: So it's it's not necessarily a linear play experience.
Speaker 0: like your first quote, playthrough is not your first actual playthrough.
Speaker 0: So an interesting thing about this game, too, is that because there are chances to see some of the different branches, like you may have made one decision.
Speaker 1: You and I played the game.
Speaker 0: You will get a chance to make a different decision.
Speaker 0: In fact, the game forces you to make different decisions.
Speaker 0: You can't do the same thing multiple times.
Speaker 1: Well, that's part of the shtick that I think is worth calling out directly, because the game hints at it.
Speaker 1: But until you encounter it explicitly, it's not that obvious.
Speaker 1: The game, as soon as you get to a point to where the only decision you like, the decision you could make is one that you have already made exactly.
Speaker 1: And there would be no difference.
Speaker 1: It will prevent you from choosing something specifically forcing you to do literally anything differently from what you did the last time you played through the loop or the game, as it were.
Speaker 0: It's kind of interesting because we've been like, especially you have been watching a lot of quantum physics videos.
Speaker 1: that plays heavily into this, as does a lot of philosophy, philosophical schools.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's a deceptively simple premise at first.
Speaker 0: And like, you know, there's not a lot of it's.
Speaker 0: it's variations on a theme.
Speaker 0: The complexity comes not from like a bunch of different settings, like, you know, Baldur's Gate, you're down in the Underdark and you're over here and you're over there.
Speaker 0: No, there's like very few settings.
Speaker 0: There's, you know, the cabin in the woods, the woods, the basement of the cabin.
Speaker 0: And that's basically it for locations.
Speaker 0: And then there's you and the princess and the narrator.
Speaker 0: And those are a lot of characters.
Speaker 0: It might not seem like a lot of characters, but when I tell you like the princess is a lot of characters.
Speaker 0: This game is important to internalize that the variation comes from these simple elements being like all the different permutations.
Speaker 1: And I would say the game is playing with a lot of very basic and core themes very similarly to how things like Neon Genesis Evangelion are like.
Speaker 1: They are talking about many of the same ideas just in a different way.
Speaker 1: And I guess what's really fascinating is you and I played very similarly, like we approached the situation largely similarly, but tiny, slight differences in decisions we made led to us seeing at some points radically different stories play out.
Speaker 0: Well, it was very interesting because my literal first encounter was very different than your first encounter with the princess.
Speaker 0: You know, she she spoke to me differently.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I was in and you did take the knife.
Speaker 1: I did take the knife and you went down to talk to her.
Speaker 1: I said basically said, fuck this.
Speaker 1: And I walked away from the cabin and found I found something.
Speaker 0: So that was that was an interesting thing.
Speaker 1: In fact, I got I got.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 1: my first encounter with the princess was the princess saying something to the effect of I'm sorry, you encountered me first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically you you tried to break the the rules before I did.
Speaker 0: I was like, well, I'm going to follow and see what like the most standard play through happens.
Speaker 0: And so because we had the very different first approaches, we had very different experiences.
Speaker 0: But it was interesting because you said you wanted to see.
Speaker 0: it was almost like a test to be like, let's see how Emily approaches this character and approaches this scenario.
Speaker 0: And actually, I think we ended up with a lot of the same because I didn't like super role play.
Speaker 1: I tried to put myself in the blank, kind of like with Disco Elysium.
Speaker 1: I put myself in the mind frame of, all right, this is all I know.
Speaker 1: What would I do?
Speaker 0: See, the thing is, you in this game, in like Disco Elysium, you are playing a character and that character has a whole history.
Speaker 1: That character is very specific.
Speaker 1: You just don't know it.
Speaker 0: So that's that's more role playing.
Speaker 0: I would say that Slay the Princess, it's it doesn't try to put much flavor on you as a player.
Speaker 1: The game even kind of says like diagetically, like in the context of the game.
Speaker 1: Look, buddy, no judgment.
Speaker 1: Well, you're not being judged by what you choose.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I can imagine watching someone play through this game and judging them.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Like the player character is also referred to whenever you get to that specific scene where the princess tell you, you know, you're not supposed to see this yet, you know, but.
Speaker 0: That character is referred to as a vessel.
Speaker 0: You're just an empty vessel.
Speaker 0: And into that vessel goes not only the different narrative voices, but also you as the player.
Speaker 0: You have all the memories of playing this game.
Speaker 0: You know what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: You have all these.
Speaker 1: And that's sort of the fun trick of the game, because you remember as a player.
Speaker 1: And it's clear that the voices in the character's head that you're playing remember.
Speaker 1: But the narrator does not remember it.
Speaker 0: It really kind of addresses directly the fact in gaming that in some ways, a character is an empty vessel into which the player pours their sense of agency.
Speaker 1: Coupled with this game is taking that and distilling it down to the simplest possible scenario of very direct binary choices and then really, really throwing the ramifications of those choices in your face and making you make increasingly difficult decisions.
Speaker 0: There are very few choices when you come right down to it, because if there were more choices, then it's exponential, because every choice matters and every choice leads to a radically different outcome.
Speaker 0: So I think it would be very difficult to make this game more complex in terms of your your decisions and having it be quite binary.
Speaker 0: Like, do you take the knife down to the basement where the princess is, or do you not take the knife down to the prince?
Speaker 1: And despite roleplaying myself and like kind of not trusting the narrator and trying to not be evil, I chose to bring the knife down there several times.
Speaker 0: Well, and sometimes, like I said, it forces you.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm just going to go right out and say it.
Speaker 1: There's a loop, you know, like there's a great moment you'll encounter early where if you try to not slay the princess, the game kind of tries to force you to.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And if you resist that happening, then you get a certain kind of scene.
Speaker 1: And if you go through the same scenario again and you still try to like not hurt the princess, you hit a point where the game says, all right, all your options, the option you chose last time is not available anymore.
Speaker 1: You have to do something bad.
Speaker 0: So there are two kinds, kind of like in Disco Elysium, there are two kinds of text, right?
Speaker 0: And two kinds of decisions.
Speaker 0: There are these binary decisions that very much change the outcome and basically give you a different princess, a different ending of this loop.
Speaker 0: And, you know, and then there are like the same questions that will be repeated, but they don't really change from play through the play through.
Speaker 1: And it sort of gets into this territory like in storytelling traditions where the repetition of the story starts to reinforce the story itself.
Speaker 1: Or think of it like the Odyssey, where you get certain phrases that are repeated over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: And the game sort of draws you into this mood of the repetition.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It always starts the same way with the narrator saying the same thing.
Speaker 1: And you have all these options to talk with them or fight with them or agree with them or whatever.
Speaker 1: But one of the options is to just silently walk on toward the cabin.
Speaker 1: And even as a player, you get to the point to where like you choose that option first on purpose, because you've seen all this before and not just in the.
Speaker 1: I'm skipping the dialog because I'm playing Final Fantasy for the hundredth time.
Speaker 1: But in the if that were me, I that's kind of how I would react.
Speaker 1: Like I'm drawn into this experience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, totally.
Speaker 0: I think it's one of those things where you also make your decisions differently based on the fact that you know, you know, your vessel is vulnerable, but basically will reincarnate over and over again.
Speaker 0: So in many cases, I would choose difficult decisions that put me as the player in danger.
Speaker 0: And it was like, well, if I do this, I will probably die.
Speaker 0: But then I was like, well, does it matter if I die?
Speaker 0: Does it matter if she dies?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like all these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, it's fascinating because you don't necessarily know right away, like what is permanent and not what happens and doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Like the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You can experience the game many different ways.
Speaker 0: And when you.
Speaker 0: If if you die, you may wake up and something is different.
Speaker 1: But then to get into some spoilers and start to talk about the deal of the game, I'd say where this really like the strength of this game ultimately is.
Speaker 1: all this is great.
Speaker 1: And it gets really deep into these sort of like ultra distilled metaphysical and philosophical concepts.
Speaker 1: And like it got stuck in my craw for a while.
Speaker 1: I chose the word craw very specifically here, independent of how I say that a lot, because I was mad that I didn't pick up on something right away.
Speaker 1: But that aside, what really puts this game from A tier to S tier for me is that despite having this Evangelion adjacent, like very broad, universal, distilled sort of story and thesis, at the same time, this game wouldn't work if it was procedurally generated.
Speaker 1: It is written and it has a specific framing and conclusion that you can discover.
Speaker 1: There is a specific story here.
Speaker 1: This is not a generic, it can be anything you want it to be.
Speaker 1: You can interpret the events as you see them in many ways.
Speaker 1: But there are some realities that are portrayed.
Speaker 1: There is a story that was intentional that Abby Howard and Tony Howard Arias and Brandon Boone want you to experience.
Speaker 0: I thought it was interesting because it gets into philosophical questions like literally existential stuff, like what is the nature of existence?
Speaker 0: You know, what is change as a as a I think a big theme is.
Speaker 1: it's about humans seeing natural selection and then maybe escaping from it or changing how they evolve.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's basically, you know, the idea of of death has metamorphosis.
Speaker 0: It's the idea of, you know, is unchanging immortal godhood or a basically a species changing and adapting and living.
Speaker 1: Death is change and change is death.
Speaker 0: And that unchanging is also death.
Speaker 0: It's like being a stone and being trapped forever in the same cycle.
Speaker 0: So I thought it was really interesting to how a lot of the things it brings up is like questions around narrative and around storytelling.
Speaker 0: So and around gaming, like the idea that characters within a game, like they don't have a memory, but you as the player have memories and the use of you remember, but other characters don't, you know, because you're a human, you're not part of the game.
Speaker 1: So at this point, because it is just an indie game, like you can just buy and play it all the way through.
Speaker 1: So we're just going to stop reviewing.
Speaker 1: I mean, the games.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend it.
Speaker 1: Anyone who listens to Geek Nights, anyone who cares about graphic novels or indie games, like you'll enjoy this.
Speaker 1: But I think from this point on, we're going to spoil stuff.
Speaker 1: And I'd recommend you not spoil this game for yourself and just go play it.
Speaker 1: In fact, I recommend if you want to try it out, other than what we've said, don't read anything about it to just literally go in and dive in and see where you end up.
Speaker 0: If I recall, the first time you were playing this game, you were playing it in the computer room and I was out in the living room and I wandered in here and you were like, oh, no, don't look at my screen.
Speaker 1: Because you saw a very Evangelion looking, multi-princess, triple mask kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I saw the mound and I saw like this very goddessy looking figure.
Speaker 0: And I was like, oh, what's that?
Speaker 0: You're like, don't look, it's mega spoilers, so stay away.
Speaker 0: So I definitely think this is a game that can be spoiled.
Speaker 0: And I would recommend, you know, just go with your heart and make the decisions the way you would normally make decisions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, what would you want to see happen if you encounter a princess in the woods with no memories and a mysterious voice saying you have to kill her or the world will end?
Speaker 0: And it kind of sucks because it automatically placed your empathy because the narrator is constantly telling you, you have to kill her or the world will end.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the first time you see her, probably, probably, you know, I'm putting a little asterisk there because you obviously encountered something very different.
Speaker 0: the first time you played through is this woman who is chained to a wall in a basement.
Speaker 0: And it's just like you automatically are like, I want to save the princess.
Speaker 0: I don't want to kill the princess.
Speaker 0: This makes me the bad guy to kill the princess.
Speaker 0: So I think I think the best thing to do is, you know, I wouldn't even say try to avoid bad endings, because there are some endings that are, quote unquote, bad.
Speaker 0: You know, that's when it gets more horror.
Speaker 0: That's when it gets spookier.
Speaker 0: But they're also very interesting.
Speaker 1: They also arguably aren't endings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not endings.
Speaker 0: That's the other thing.
Speaker 1: It's like I think they're all good.
Speaker 1: I think that's the key.
Speaker 1: Every direction you could take in this game, even the hyper violent, empathy free, I'm going to kill the princess.
Speaker 1: And yeah, it says you get a really interesting ending.
Speaker 1: You can basically.
Speaker 0: basically there are two only two meaningful choices that I can think of in this this game.
Speaker 0: I guess three, when you come down to it, you can choose to go to the cabin, not go to the cabin.
Speaker 0: You can choose to take the knife down to the basement or not take the knife with you.
Speaker 0: And you can choose whether to kill the princess, you know.
Speaker 1: And in that final round is when you get all those micro decisions, like depending on how you fight and how you react, you get a lot of subtly different paths.
Speaker 1: And like the final bit before the end of each segment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, within each individual path, like I guess I kind of want to talk about our respective journeys, which shared a lot of things.
Speaker 0: We saw a lot of the same princesses, but one of the fundamental conceits is these multiple playthroughs.
Speaker 0: They are supposed to be very different.
Speaker 0: And you're supposed to like you.
Speaker 0: You're gathering memories for a goddess.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's one interpretation.
Speaker 1: I'm very happy that I mean, there is a. you know, we said this game has a literal interpretation.
Speaker 1: And I like the fact that if you eventually corner the narrator and the narrator is like, look, buddy, here's what's going on.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of a specific story at that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very much about existence and gods and memories.
Speaker 0: Like the princess basically is more, I don't know, wants to experience many different pathways.
Speaker 0: And you are a vessel interacting because she can't interact directly.
Speaker 0: And so you with your agency as a player are bringing her these different endings, these different pathways.
Speaker 0: And so after each death, usually your own, you kind of go through this, I don't know, literal post-mortem with her.
Speaker 0: And she's like, well, this was a princess who could not trust.
Speaker 1: And I think that's what colored the game for me very specifically, is the first princess I encountered was the mound explaining what she wanted out of everything.
Speaker 1: Before I even really interacted with the narrator, before I met a normal princess, before I got any endings, I met the mound and the mound told me exactly what to do.
Speaker 0: And this was very, this was a very you thing to do.
Speaker 1: Because if I woke up with amnesia in the woods and all I knew was what I saw before me, and a voice told me to go kill somebody with the knife, I would question it and try to figure out where I am.
Speaker 1: Like as even Star Trek style.
Speaker 1: Am I in the holodeck?
Speaker 1: Did I wake up in the holodeck?
Speaker 0: So immediately what you did, which totally tracks with your personality and what I know about how you think about the world, is you started to probe the borders of the reality of this game.
Speaker 0: You're like, well, you say I have to go deal with the princess.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to walk in the opposite direction.
Speaker 0: And so immediately you broke these confines.
Speaker 0: You said, I am not going to follow your narrative flow.
Speaker 0: And thus you immediately went into the metanarrative.
Speaker 0: You got to the meta part of the game.
Speaker 0: So I took something, I took a much more traditional route.
Speaker 0: I was like, I don't want to kill a princess.
Speaker 0: That sounds bad.
Speaker 0: But I went to the cabin.
Speaker 0: I took the knife with me because I didn't know what to expect.
Speaker 0: And I got a princess who was very human, but was also more hostile toward me.
Speaker 1: Which makes sense.
Speaker 1: You're locked up with no memories either.
Speaker 0: And I go down into her dungeon with a knife.
Speaker 1: A little bird comes in with a knife and is like, hey.
Speaker 0: That's another thing.
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 1: I was mad I missed that.
Speaker 1: The whole game.
Speaker 1: One of the voices, the romantic, keeps it like, oh.
Speaker 1: I would preen my feathers.
Speaker 1: And he refers to himself with bird allegories and bird references.
Speaker 0: You're very humanoid crow.
Speaker 0: Whenever you see your hands as the character.
Speaker 1: That's a good first beat.
Speaker 1: The first time you see the mirror and you reach for it and you see your non-human hand.
Speaker 0: You've got these dragon-y, scaly hands.
Speaker 0: And so it's another interesting thing.
Speaker 0: Because you, the human player, is inhabiting the vessel that is a non-human character.
Speaker 0: So anyway.
Speaker 0: So our starts were very different.
Speaker 0: But we ended up trying-- one, we both played empathetic.
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: We both were trying to figure out if there was a way in which to spare the princess and spare the world.
Speaker 0: But there isn't really a way to spare the world because the world is just the story.
Speaker 1: The world is just your egg.
Speaker 0: Also, it's, again, like I said, it's a lot about fiction writing.
Speaker 0: This thing, it can be read as like a mythic narrative about gods and existence.
Speaker 0: But it can also just be talking about fiction.
Speaker 0: It's basically like the end of a story is the end.
Speaker 0: Like the narrator's life ends when the story ends.
Speaker 0: And so each retelling, the narrator dies.
Speaker 0: And so his world essentially vanishes.
Speaker 0: But you remember it, so it doesn't completely vanish.
Speaker 1: Of course, the narrator doesn't seem to care necessarily that its world dies.
Speaker 1: Because one of my favorite moments in the game is when, if you finally-- you get to look in the mirror, and then you notice something, and then you talk to the narrator directly.
Speaker 1: And the narrator, early on, like I said before, explains, it doesn't work if you know what's going on.
Speaker 1: Like if I share information, none of this will work.
Speaker 1: And then when cornered, I love that section where you get to ask the narrator a limited number of questions.
Speaker 0: You're breaking different pieces.
Speaker 0: It's all shattered.
Speaker 0: And every little shard you click on is a question.
Speaker 0: And then once you're out of shards, you're out of time and answers.
Speaker 1: And I guess it was the story itself.
Speaker 1: from a pure, direct, face value, science fiction, fantasy standpoint, much like things like your tenet and other works we like, it works on every level.
Speaker 1: And from that standpoint, we get that explanation that the narrator was a construct made by, assumedly, a god of some kind.
Speaker 1: And you are a new god.
Speaker 1: And it basically locked you in a cage or an egg or in a construct that it created to force you to use your godlike powers to kill what it perceived as the concept of death.
Speaker 0: But death is change.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, it doesn't know or care.
Speaker 1: It seems like the narrator is almost a semi-sentient construct.
Speaker 1: It's like a program that was left behind to run inside of your egg.
Speaker 0: It's basically like saying we want perfect, unchanging immortality.
Speaker 0: And so you need to attack chaos.
Speaker 0: You need to attack the very concept of decision-making.
Speaker 1: Well, I love how it describes the princess as we're going to kill death, basically.
Speaker 1: And if you look at what's actually going on, it really is almost an inversion of you are death sent to kill life itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the princess, in a way, is kind of like the concept of, well, I like the idea that it's the concept of change, because often, in order for something to change, the old version has to die, whether literally or metaphorically.
Speaker 0: We talked about natural selection.
Speaker 0: We talked about that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But I think it's worth noting that change, by its very nature, overwrites what the existing state of something, even if it's an addition, you know, you add memories to this princess and she changes because these new experiences have been added.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But she's also portrayed as, like, it's interesting that every time you finish a story and the princess dies and feels cold and is sort of like she's gone and the mound remembers, but it's heavily implied that the individual vessels die.
Speaker 0: Species versus individual, maybe?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why I get back to this natural selection idea, because what stuck with me the most from this game was the construct telling you, the player, this doesn't work if you see what's happening.
Speaker 1: If you understand the situation, none of this works anymore.
Speaker 0: You could also look at this as one of those stories about escaping a time loop.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things that have that kind of Groundhog Day type of repetition.
Speaker 0: But this is like, you can choose to either stay in a perfect deathless loop, or you can step outside that into the chaotic and in some ways...
Speaker 1: Well, the game calls it absolute reality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's a world where causality exists.
Speaker 0: It's a world where, you know, these choices matter and death happens and change is the predominant force.
Speaker 0: So I think that is the interesting... I don't even think that you, the player character, is necessarily a god.
Speaker 0: I almost feel like...
Speaker 1: You're told you're a god.
Speaker 1: Maybe because I asked different questions, but they told me straight up, you are a new god that my creator also created you to kill her.
Speaker 0: But the princess also treats you as a vessel and each...
Speaker 1: Well, the mound treats you as a vessel.
Speaker 1: The princess treats you...
Speaker 0: The mound is composed of princess memories of all.
Speaker 0: It's basically like an amalgamation of all these different narrative paths you could have walked.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like in quantum theory.
Speaker 0: It's like all the different possible routes a particle can take.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's talk a little bit about some of the individual princesses and what they meant to you.
Speaker 1: Once I enjoyed this, one of the loop endings I got was we just sat together.
Speaker 1: I ended up chaining myself up next to her and we just waited.
Speaker 1: We sat there and eventually the world crumbles around us and we just have a chat and contemplate the universe and then the mound takes her.
Speaker 1: The most fun one, I think, was still the witch because she's very...
Speaker 0: She's spiky.
Speaker 0: You like those kind of spiky monster girls and she looks kind of lion-like.
Speaker 1: She reminds me of all things yin zu ha from the second Tenchi Muyo movie.
Speaker 1: Very like, "I'm a little kobold with a
Speaker 1: knife.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, kobold is a good descriptor.
Speaker 0: Kobolds have been coming up a lot lately, but...
Speaker 1: Oh, we both did the same thing with her.
Speaker 0: Kind of animal-like but not the beast.
Speaker 1: We knew we'd hurt her and we had to gain her trust back and we both just handed her the knife.
Speaker 0: And then she immediately stabs you and was like, "Why did you give me the knife?
Speaker 0: You knew this was going to
Speaker 0: happen.".
Speaker 0: And as you're dying, you're like, "Yeah, I
Speaker 0: understand.".
Speaker 1: But then you get the thorn after that, which is one of the better written ones.
Speaker 0: I think the thorn was probably my favorite moment, so...
Speaker 1: Well, the thorn is subtle because one thing the thorn does is... You didn't have the narrator tell you this at that point because you've done a slightly different path.
Speaker 1: But because I had the narrator tell me, "This doesn't work if you know what's going on,".
Speaker 1: that was when I figured stuff... A lot of basics of what was going on out is during the thorn because the narrator is trying to convince you not to even try and that's when you realize you can just push the thorns aside.
Speaker 1: Nothing is actually in your way because the entire environment is you.
Speaker 1: You are the god of this world.
Speaker 0: You decide.
Speaker 0: You're like, "Make the thorns part before you and you can just leave.
Speaker 0: You can just hit the
Speaker 0: bricks.".
Speaker 1: The narrator's like, "Well,
Speaker 1: fuck.".
Speaker 0: And I think a big part of that also was the idea of you have wounded each other because I believe you only get to the witch if you don't kill the princess.
Speaker 1: If you try to kill her and you don't warn her.
Speaker 0: You stab at her.
Speaker 0: You wound her.
Speaker 0: You wound her greatly and then you die.
Speaker 0: And then when you come back, she's now this tricksy, sort of evil beast-like creature who's like, "Well, not full
Speaker 0: beast.".
Speaker 1: The full beast is also a really fascinating one.
Speaker 0: That's where the vore comes in.
Speaker 0: Because she can eat you as a monster.
Speaker 1: There's a lot.
Speaker 1: One thing, I was looking at the map of the game.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of micro decisions that lead to a lot of very different scenes in those third acts.
Speaker 1: The piece can go a bunch of different ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could stab at her in the stomach.
Speaker 1: That was the one time when I went in after the witch.
Speaker 1: When I went back in, I figured she was still mad.
Speaker 1: So I brought the knife with me anyway when the beast situation was happening.
Speaker 1: And as soon as I realized it was a den and she bit me.
Speaker 1: And you kind of just backed off and got super passive and then she bit you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and she ate me.
Speaker 0: I stabbed her back.
Speaker 1: Like, "Look, you can't just bite
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 0: You have teeth.
Speaker 0: I have teeth too.
Speaker 0: Stab.
Speaker 0: And she was like, "Okay.
Speaker 0: Oh.".
Speaker 1: That one's fun because she's starting to figure things out too.
Speaker 1: She is actively trying to escape, which the narrator keeps saying.
Speaker 1: She's eventually going to break out whether you kill her or not.
Speaker 1: Like, no matter what you do, if you don't kill her, she's eventually getting out.
Speaker 0: You made fun of me during my playthrough because you're like, "You are way too sub... You're not way too...
Speaker 1: You are very
Speaker 1: submissive.".
Speaker 1: That's how you got the dominant mistress.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: She was like another legend.
Speaker 0: There was like a goddess.
Speaker 0: I forget her actual name.
Speaker 0: There was a specific, like, philosophical term for that one.
Speaker 0: Like, it started with a...
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the princesses.
Speaker 1: If you play the game once or twice, read the wiki to see the names of all of them, like the witch, the raven.
Speaker 1: Or the specter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fury.
Speaker 0: Like, there's one that isn't just swords.
Speaker 1: You got the apotheosis.
Speaker 1: The games quote, "This one is dominance.
Speaker 1: A figure capable of bending everything to her will.
Speaker 1: She will make for a terrifying and divine heart.
Speaker 1: Do not mourn for her, for she cannot mourn for
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically she turns into, like, this radiant goddess.
Speaker 0: And I immediately was like, "I worship you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you're above
Speaker 0: everything.".
Speaker 1: Every time that kind of situation happened, I bit back a little.
Speaker 1: Like, I pecked at her.
Speaker 1: like, "Hey,
Speaker 1: look.".
Speaker 0: Like, you pecked at her.
Speaker 1: You get told you have a beak at one point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you get little, little kind of not straight on glimpses, but little kind of...
Speaker 1: I mean, when she gets pissed, she calls you little bird at one point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a bunch of references to you being basically a crow with teeth.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you're this humanoid corvid and kind of dragon-y, kind of just, you know, inhuman.
Speaker 0: But yeah, apparently if you fight her there, if you fight the goddess, you have, like, this huge back and forth and she actually respects you too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I figured that once you get into those spicier endings, I guess our different philosophies was, "I figured if she's game for a fight, we're going to have a
Speaker 1: fight.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, I liked when you were like, "Yeah, I stabbed the beast," and she was kind of like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: ah.".
Speaker 1: She still ate me.
Speaker 1: But she was being tricksy there because then she even explains like, "Yeah, I swallowed you but didn't kill you.
Speaker 1: Last time when I killed you, I wrapped your body... I couldn't get up.
Speaker 1: I, like, dragged your body to the door and I still couldn't get through, so I figured you had to be alive.
Speaker 0: She couldn't get up the stairs.
Speaker 1: But you're not going to let me out.
Speaker 1: I'm going to use you as a key to get myself out of
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, she did spit me out eventually.
Speaker 0: It wasn't too great.
Speaker 0: I was pretty fucked up.
Speaker 1: She didn't spit me out and then the mound took her while I was inside her.
Speaker 0: That's weird.
Speaker 1: Which was a cool ending in one sense because when the mound takes her, you get an extra little scene where you're laying there like,
Speaker 1: "Ow!".
Speaker 1: And then she is begging the mound, like, yelling at the mound, "Why didn't it take you two?
Speaker 1: Why is it just taking
Speaker 1: her?".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: A lot of the ones, she kind of is, like, surprised.
Speaker 0: Like, she gets outside, she's happy, like,
Speaker 0: "Yay!".
Speaker 0: And then she's like, "Ooh, it's
Speaker 0: cold.".
Speaker 1: Well, because natural selection is the way we've evolved as living beings.
Speaker 1: Natural selection means death is the only thing that evolves us.
Speaker 0: And we were talking, again, this is a good thing for our meta-contextualism essay.
Speaker 0: This is a meta-contextualist game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're going to write an essay.
Speaker 1: This, the Spider-Verse, actually Rick and Morty, everything everywhere all at once.
Speaker 1: Half the art in the Magfest artist alley last year.
Speaker 0: We were talking a lot about the idea of the multiverse, and we were talking a lot about, like, the kind of variations on a theme, or the idea that a narrative is not necessarily linear, and it has a lot of, like, potential endings and potential branches, or maybe no endings at all, question mark.
Speaker 0: An end is a beginning.
Speaker 0: But the other thing we noticed is a lot of references to decay and metamorphosis, and not necessarily in a negative context.
Speaker 0: It was almost like kind of Victorian memento mori, sort of like romanticization of death and decay.
Speaker 0: Like, lots of fungal motifs, lots of skeletons, and- Animals, but the animals are, like, running around.
Speaker 1: Also, the multi-eye aesthetic is popping up in, like, every Tumblr kid's art everywhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know how that relates to meta-contextualism, but it's like the third eye you see with all these different eyes.
Speaker 1: I've seen minor rumblings online of the multi-eyes are almost evocative of old Christian, like, multi-dimensional angels.
Speaker 0: Oh, like multi-dimensional angels.
Speaker 0: I can see that.
Speaker 1: A greater being, I'm making finger quotes, that sees from more perspectives than just one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I said, the third eye or, you know, the multi-eye thing where, you know, the human eyes peer into reality, whereas, you know, other eyes can peer beyond this material plane.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's kind of an interesting way to look at narrative, and I think having it be a game is very important, because it's a bit choose your own adventure, like a lot of these visual novels are, but it's more cyclical.
Speaker 0: It's more cyclical, but not completely, you know, you can't make the same story multiple times.
Speaker 0: And one thing that is worth noting is, like, okay, so we both started very compassionate.
Speaker 0: We're like, we will never hurt the princess.
Speaker 0: You're not able to get away with it.
Speaker 1: I love this game also, and credit to Abby Howard, it plays with the tropes of visual novels.
Speaker 1: Like, there's a one player, and it's like, you just get a hundred options all lined up that are all just slay the princess.
Speaker 1: And if you scroll all the way down, there's one buried in the middle that says spare the princess.
Speaker 0: And so I clicked that, and then the next time I played it almost identically.
Speaker 1: And then that one's grayed out.
Speaker 0: And then it's grayed out, and you can't do that.
Speaker 0: So you have to pick one of the other, like, bajillion options that are just like, you have to stab.
Speaker 0: And it's also kind of funny because when you spare the princess, like, the narrator tries to force your hand, and the princess ends up killing you.
Speaker 1: That's one of the funniest moments when she, like, closes her eyes and is like, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: Randomly stabbing at you.
Speaker 0: And it's probably in a game full of grisly deaths.
Speaker 0: It is one of the more painfully described deaths where she just can't really keep getting tendons to get you long.
Speaker 1: But she has to finish.
Speaker 0: You're just kind of slowly bleeding out being like, I'm sorry, I understand.
Speaker 0: This sucks.
Speaker 0: And also, you don't know necessarily you're going to reincarnate because often that's one of the first first loops.
Speaker 0: So I think that also really controlled how I approached the game was.
Speaker 0: you do start to feel like you're kind of immortal.
Speaker 0: You also expect to suffer.
Speaker 0: So it's like by your suffering, you free her from her chains.
Speaker 1: And the fact that your character does remember implies that you're greater than the vessels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you are like the mound and the princesses are not.
Speaker 0: You're just like this disposable pop up dragon that they let you go.
Speaker 0: Little monster.
Speaker 0: You can go in and then, you know, when we're done with you, we'll just make another one.
Speaker 1: And in a way there, you're almost molding the princess the same way that natural selection would, like killing them.
Speaker 0: And that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: She does remember certain things like if you stab her, that's going to affect how she goes in the neck.
Speaker 0: Like decisions within the play through affect it.
Speaker 0: Like, do you have the knife?
Speaker 0: Do you not have the knife?
Speaker 0: But specifically, the one that makes a big difference is, do you kill her?
Speaker 0: You know, do you?
Speaker 0: And often it surprises you with how that goes down.
Speaker 1: What I appreciated too was when you start to when you figure out and learn in the game that you're in a construct and then the narrator is gone and everything, you realize that the long quiet and the background that appears every time you're by yourself or just with the narrator, it's very clearly your wings furled around yourself.
Speaker 1: Because when the game ends, if you leave, then it describes like pressing like feathers.
Speaker 1: You fan your wings out and you feel a barrier and you break through it like you're breaking out of an egg.
Speaker 1: And then you get this vague image of like a giant winged god out in the cosmos.
Speaker 0: What is that quote from?
Speaker 0: I forget who it's from, but it's in Utena.
Speaker 0: Well, all the student council says it as they go up in the elevator.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's from Herman S. Demian.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Demian.
Speaker 0: And it's basically like the chick must smash itself to be born.
Speaker 1: From the story of a boyhood about a bird wrestling its way out of its egg.
Speaker 1: And really it's about boys coming of age.
Speaker 0: So I want to say we have that book.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I read it a long time ago when we were doing that show doing lit crit on Utena.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's another thing where it's like characters questioning their own reality and becoming more because they're kind of trapped within a cycle.
Speaker 1: But ultimately in the end, I like that we both, when you're confronted with the full reality of the constructs and you have to decide what to do, we both basically decided to break out into absolute reality with the princess knowing everything she could be.
Speaker 1: I think I'd rather... Go out alone.
Speaker 1: And I wasn't going to stay in my egg forever.
Speaker 0: But that's the question.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, would you rather live?
Speaker 0: Would you rather live, period?
Speaker 0: Like living is a certain amount of suffering, a certain amount of imperfection.
Speaker 0: Would you rather like static, unchanging, angelic, like nothingness?
Speaker 0: Or would you rather the messy chaos of existence?
Speaker 1: Well, it goes further, too, because that is the same dichotomy that Neon Genesis Evangelion delves in in the original show.
Speaker 1: And in the remake, it triples down on that.
Speaker 1: when you get to see minor spoilers for Evangelion.
Speaker 1: You basically see the universe as Gendo wants it and what it would be if Gendo achieved everything he wanted.
Speaker 1: And it's just him alone in a giant, cool ship being a sad sack for all of eternity.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's basically the whole point of Neon Genesis Evangelion was basically, you know, the hedgehog's dilemma.
Speaker 0: Vulnerability and letting people in often hurts you.
Speaker 0: You know, it's difficult.
Speaker 0: You can never truly connect because we're all individuals.
Speaker 0: But you have to try to let people in.
Speaker 0: You have to try to connect and be a part of the world instead of walling yourself off in your own little cell.
Speaker 1: But the other thing it evokes very strongly is the the singularity versus duality concept that appears in a lot of philosophy and a lot of literature in the sense that some of what the construct says, depending on what you ask, basically implies that there was one god and the person who made the construct basically clove that god in two and wanted to kill half of it.
Speaker 1: But that implies, too, that your choice is.
Speaker 1: that is is also is there just one thing or are there two things that might not agree or possibly more things, which is very close to, again, what Evangelion was all out about?
Speaker 0: Wouldn't you say that?
Speaker 0: So if you consider that the player character is a god, what do you think they are god of?
Speaker 1: That is complicated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you you talked a lot about the mound, about being a singularity, about being natural selection, although what do you think you the player represents?
Speaker 1: I mean, the game seems to imply that you are effectively death.
Speaker 1: You are described as the long quiet.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, in some ways that really makes sense, because if the princess is...
Speaker 1: Between every act, you go back to the long quiet.
Speaker 1: At the end, the narrator calls you the long quiet.
Speaker 1: It basically says that's your name.
Speaker 0: In some ways, you could kind of think about it like, if there's no life, there's also no death.
Speaker 0: You know, how do we end death?
Speaker 0: by ending life?
Speaker 1: So you can be immortal and unchanging.
Speaker 0: Yeah, by getting rid of change, by getting rid of the living things, then there is no more death.
Speaker 1: But also the mound can't evolve without death.
Speaker 1: And that's why I come back to that natural selection idea, because it reminded me of that story that had a recent fairly well animated YouTube video, The Goddess of Everything Else.
Speaker 1: And the idea that if the construct only works because you don't understand what's happening, once you understand it and you emerge into the world as a god, it's you and the mound are the two things in the universe effectively.
Speaker 1: And at that point, you can interact with each other, but the mound is as immortal as you are.
Speaker 1: So there can still be change without necessarily death, but that's a different mode of being.
Speaker 1: It's almost like transcending the previous order.
Speaker 0: Well, death changes life.
Speaker 1: I mean, imagine a distant future where conscious sentience evolves without ever having to die, but changes radically.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the classic story of the thousand year old elf, who is a fundamentally different person now, but is one contiguous chain of experience and memories, but it still changes.
Speaker 1: But it's a different kind of death from, well, you're just dead.
Speaker 0: Gone forever.
Speaker 0: Think no thoughts anymore.
Speaker 1: What child that you had.
Speaker 1: or your memes, maybe infect other people down the road, but you don't get to experience any of that.
Speaker 0: Interesting stuff.
Speaker 1: And on that note, sketchily drawn visual novel, body horror, eldritch story game.
Speaker 0: I think it was well worth under 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: You know, I would definitely recommend this game if any of this stuff sounded interesting.
Speaker 0: And I'm assuming if you've listened this far, you're either never going to play the game and you just want to hear a CMR about it, or you have played the game and wanted to hear other people.
Speaker 1: I hope if you haven't played the game that you're at least intrigued.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should still play it, even though we've spoiled some stuff and told you about the stuff behind the curtain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because mechanically, one thing the game does well.
Speaker 0: Break down the set and go behind it.
Speaker 1: Every choice you can click on matters and does something interesting.
Speaker 1: Nothing is boring.
Speaker 1: There is literally no direction you can go where nothing uninteresting happens.
Speaker 1: There's always something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, highly recommended.
Speaker 1: A surprising number of options in some of these stories.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowclue.com for show notes, discussion, links, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays, gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 international license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this special episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Lynn Gucci, Dred Lillie, Tana Burke, history makes music, Chris Adoch, Christopher Orr, Clinton, Walton, Finn, Jule Hayes, Penny Reimer, Rebecca Nunn, Sam Erickson, Shurmur, Matt Holen, a bunch of people whose names I will not name.
Speaker 1: So I'll let you all know we tried out Adobe Podcasts to do this episode with some mixed results.
Speaker 1: I feel like Adobe Podcasts is not stable.
Speaker 1: It actually crashed a couple times.
Speaker 1: We were able to recover the audio without having to resort to extreme backup shenanigans.
Speaker 1: The audio processing is only okay, so let us know how this one sounds, because I'm still experimenting with this stuff, but I feel like for the foreseeable future, Geek Nights, regardless of if it is a special or just the regular old me and Scott, will continue to use the old pipeline and not migrate anything to Adobe Podcasts at this time.
Speaker 1: But otherwise, I highly recommend you play Slay This Princess.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we will see you at PAX West.
Speaker 1: And so tonight, I leave you with... Bitzy, you told us that your town was going to kick you out forever, and you don't even seem upset about that.
Speaker 0: They keep asking me to leave, and I didn't leave, and then they were going to tell me to kick out, and then I was going to be kicked out, and I was like, I don't want that to happen.
Speaker 1: Why were they going to kick you out?
Speaker 0: Because they don't understand the difference between lemons and lemon juice.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: It's a long story, you wouldn't understand.
Speaker 0: I'm really trying.
Speaker 0: If they had to kick you out because they didn't understand the difference between lemons and lemon juice, we might have to kick you out if we don't understand the difference between lemons and lemon juice.
Speaker 1: Well, the one is the lemon, and then the other's like a liquidy juice type.
Speaker 0: They kept saying that one came from the other, and that's f***ing horsesh*t. Clearly the juice comes from the lemon, but once you squeeze the juice out of the lemon, it hence, it stops being a lemon.
Speaker 0: This is what they kept saying, that doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: I don't have any lemons on me, but if you squeeze that lemon and lemon juice, I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: All right, when we get to click clock, I am going to blow your mind.